[Music]
if you work with financial reporting in
business Central we have a few things
coming up in the 2025 release way one
that you might like so let's let me show
you what we are cooking on
here the first thing you notice is that
we have a new field called internal
description this allows you as a report
author to describe what this report is
for as an internal description the
description column here is as you can
see on the tool tip actually a heading
in the report so you don't want to put
any internal description here but you
can do that in internal description how
do you do that well let me go to the
balance sheet here as an example and um
if I want to change any definition I
choose definitions and edit report
definition and now I can say this is our
report for
year close something like that and uh
that's that's your internal description
what else did we do well if you looked
carefully when I chose definitions
there's also a new menu item here a new
action
edit introductory and closing
paragraphs this allows you to put some
text uh above and below the financial
report that will then be shown when you
export to PDF or to excel so maybe we
would put something like this is a
[Music]
preliminary
version so maybe very important for us
to say that this is not the final one
and maybe I could say something like uh
checked by
internal
oror cany on top it then my little side
hustle as in the auditing business all
right now let's try to run uh a pdf
version of the report I choose preview
and close and let's see what
happens there you go you have the
preliminary version here and in if I
scroll down to the end of the
report I have the checked by internal
auditor uh right here so that was the
second
feature now the third thing I want to
show you is related
to accountants and Auditors some some of
you don't really like if I uh let me
just hide
my
um sorry let's let's go back and just
open this in in View mode and hide my
options so I get a little bit more
screen real estate so if you notice the
the numbers here on the balance sheet if
I scroll down here to liabilities you
can see my my liabilities are shown with
negative numbers but I'm of the school
where I actually want to see these
formatted it in a common accounting way
so let's just show options and a
new a new part of this menu is called
negative amount format I can choose
parenthesis instead I hide my options
now and just scroll down a little bit
you can see now I get my number
with
parenthesis uh the negative numbers um
instead of a minus sign and this is also
reflected when I export this to PDF if I
go down on the request page options I
can choose
my uh around format here if I choose
parenthesis now and preview you can see
my my negative numbers down here are
shown with parenthesis instead of a
minor sign so these are some of the new
features in the financial reporting we
have a lot more here so you'll have to
wait for another video to see that maybe
in what's cooking or maybe in the
business Central launch event